Guide to the Claudia Brenner papers, 1988-1990.
Brenner, Claudia papers, 1988-1990.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Claudia Brenner papers, 1988-1990.
7631
Claudia, Brenner 1956-
1 cubic ft.
Publications, photographs, manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Newspaper clippings about the attack and murder, the prosecution of of Carr, controversial coverage of the story by the Ithaca Journal, and Brenner's activities since then. Also, photographs of her with NGLTF staff and Senator Paul Simon, and files from her public speaking and activism on the issue. Transcripts of two tapes she made after the attack, which used in writing her book. An "evidence tag" that was placed on her backpack. Audio and videocassettes.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Architect, author, and speaker about anti-gay violence. In 1988 Brenner and her lover Rebecca Wight were attacked by Stephen Roy Carr while they were camping along the Appalachian Trail. The gunshots wounded Brenner and killed Wight. She collaborated with the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force and their Anti-Violence Project headed by Kevin Berrill.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Newspaper clippings about the attack and murder, the prosecution of of Carr, controversial coverage of the story by the Ithaca Journal, and Brenner's activities since then. Also, photographs of her with NGLTF staff and Senator Paul Simon, and files from her public speaking and activism on the issue. Transcripts of two tapes she made after the attack, which used in writing her book. An "evidence tag" that was placed on her backpack. Audio and videocassettes.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brenner, Claudia,1956-; Carr, Stephen Roy.; Wight, Rebecca.; National Gay and Lesbian Task Force (U.S.).Anti-Violence Project.
Subjects:
Homophobia.; Lesbian activists.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Use Restrictions:
Due to the fragility and potential degradation of moving image and sound recordings, viewing and listening is limited to items that have been digitized. If an item is in another media format, you may request to have the item digitized for access. Information on ordering access copies may be found on our Reproductions and Permissions page.
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Evidence Tag (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Medical Bills (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ben & Jerry's Foundation (Box 1, Folder 3)
- National Gay Rights Advocates (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Work with NGLTF 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- NGLTF Press Conference June 7, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Someplace to Turn" NGLTF Fundraising 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Photos with NGLTF Staff (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Transcript of interview with Brenner (1990) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Misc. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ithaca Journal Story June 24, 1988 and protest letters (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Clippings on hate crimes (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Sally Raphael, anti-gay violence, Claudia Brenner, 1989-07-06; V-10454 (Box 1)
  Videocassette
- Surviving anti-gay viloence: a victim's perspective, 1991-07-27; tr-16619; Brenner, Claudia (Box 1)
  Audiocassette
- CTB fresh air, 1995-07-26; tr-16620 (Box 1)
- Claudia and Rebecca's story, part 1, Undated; tr-16621 (Box 1)
- Rebecca and Claudia, II tape, Undated; tr-16622 (Box 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings - trial and case (Box 2, Folder 2)